Michael Browning: engineer,
(مايكل براونينج): مهندس،
innovator --
مبتكر --
inventor, really --
مخترع، في الحقيقة --
and inspiring father.
وأب ملهم.
He had a passion for flight, as you can kind of sense
كان لديه حلم بالطيران، كما يمكنكم أن تتصورا
from that rather dubious 1970s office-leaving present.
من هدية التقاعد الغريبة من الـسبعينيات.
And some 40 years after that was created,
وبعد ذلك حوالي 40 عاما تم تكوين
a small group of us got together
مجموعة صغيرة منا اجتمعوا
to have a go,
لكي نجرب،
a run at the whole challenge of flight that inspired people for years,
ونشارك في التحدي الكامل للطيران الذي ألهم الناس لسنوات،
and do it in a very different kind of way.
ونحققه بطريقة مختلفة نوعا ما.
And that's the journey I'd like to share with you now.
وهي الرحلة التي أود مشراكتكم بها الآن.
The starting hypothesis was one of the human mind and body,
فرضية البدء كانت متعلقة بالعقل والجسم،
which, as you've seen for the last few days here,
والتي، كما رأيتم هنا في الأيام القلية الماضية،
is an amazing construct.
بنيان مذهل.
What if you augmented that wonderful machine
ماذا لو قمنا بتعزيز هذه الماكينة العجيبة
with just the right technology?
بالتقنية الصحيحة؟
If you approach flight in that kind of real way,
لو ستتوجه لأن تطير بهذه الطريقة الحقيقية،
where could you get to?
إلى أين سيقودك ذلك؟
So my training partner here back in London, Denton,
شريك التدريب من لندن، (دينتون)،
is doing a much better job of that kind of stuff than me.
يقوم يفوقني مهارة في تلك الأشياء التي يقوم بها.
Guess what? It's London.
خمن ماذا؟ إنها لندن.
The idea was that you augment that.
الفكرة كانت أن تقوم بهذا التعزيز.
And so, how do you augment that?
وهكذا، كيف يمكنك تعزيز ذلك؟
Well, we bought one of these.
حسنا، قمنا بإحضار واحدة من هذه
This is a micro gas turbine.
هذه توربينات غازية صغيرة.
This was ground zero,
هذه كانت نقطة البدء،
so that little piece of kit proved really quite impressive,
هذه الأدوات ثبت جدواها بشكل مبهر،
so we got two in a field.
فأتينا بإثنتين إلى الموقع.
The real hero here, by the way, is, right in the background,
البطل الحقيقي هنا، بالمناسبة، في خلفية الصورة،
there's a lady tending some vegetables,
امرأة ترعي بعض الخضروات،
who does a brilliant job of trying to ignore us for a while --
والتي تقوم بعمل رائع محاولة تجاهلنا لبرهة --
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I think the only thing less happy is the grass,
أعتقد أن الأقل سعادة هي تلك الحشائش،
that we did probably damage quite badly.
والتي من المحتمل أن أتلفناها بشكل سيء.
You get an idea of the thrust here,
تحصلون على فكرة الدفع هنا،
when I try to hold them horizontally and somewhat fail.
عندما أحاول أن أجعلها في وضع أفقي وأفشل في ذلك.
That's around 50 kilos of thrust there.
هذا حوالي 50 كيلو من الدفع هنا.
We were quite impressed with that.
كنا منبهرين تماما بذلك.
We thought we were getting somewhere.
اعتقدنا أننا نحقق تقدما.
So there's only one sensible way to go from there:
هناك طريقة منطقية وحيدة لنتبعها عند تلك المرحلة:
you get four.
أن نأتي بأربعة.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I have to say, I still like watching these back.
يجب أن أقول، أنني أحب أن أشاهد ذلك من جديد.
So then we thought well, let's try and spread the load a bit.
بعد ذلك فكرنا، حسنا، لنوزع الحمل قليلا.
The legs are designed to take the load,
السقان مصممان على أخذ الحمل،
so why don't we spread it out a bit?
فلم لا نوزعه قليلا؟
That bit was good.
هذا القليل كان جيدا.
The harness --
الظفيرة --
a nice idea but it didn't really work,
فكرة لطيفة ولكنها لم تنجح،
as you'll see now.
كما سترون الآن.
This whole journey was very much about trying things --
الرحلة بأكملها كانت عبارة عن تجربة للأشياء --
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Yeah, it really didn't work, did it?
نعم، لم تنجح، أليس كذلك؟
Trying things and learning by failing at them most of the time.
تجربة الأشياء والتعلم من الفشل في استخدامها معظم الوقت.
And that included failing by falling over.
وذلك يتضمن الفشل بالسقوط.
If you notice, we've got five engines here --
لو تلاحظون، لدينا خمسة محركات هنا --
not to be put off by the fact one was in maintenance,
ناهيك عن حققة أن أحدها كان تحت أعمال الصيانة،
still had a go.
ولكن في أمكانه العمل.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And then I pinched a fuel line.
ثم قمت بالضغط على خط الوقود.
So again, good learning. We learned not to do that again.
ومرة أخرى، درس جيد تعلمناه. تعلمنا ألا نقوم بذلك ثانية.
This was a blind alley.
ذلك كان طريق مسدود.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
This was three on each arm --
ذلك باستخدام ثلاثة لكل ذراع --
that was ridiculous.
ذلك كان سخيفا.
That was 70 kilos on each arm.
كان الوزن 70 كيلو لكل ذراع.
Again, struck that one off.
مرة أخرى، احذف هذا البند.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
But we were starting to make some really quite convincing progress,
ولكننا كنا بدأنا في إحراز تقدم مقنع،
just enough to make you believe that maybe --
تقدم كاف ليجعلك تؤمن أنه ربما --
maybe we could get there.
ربنا نستطيع أن نصل للنهاية.
You can see, look -- tantalizing.
يمكنك أن ترى، انظر -- مثير.
The model of one on each leg and two on each arm,
نموذج محرك لكل ساق واثنان لكل ذراع،
on paper, that was enough thrust.
كان ذلك على الورق يمثل دفعا كاف.
And then we did what I'm about to show you now,
بعد ذلك قمنا بما سأريكم الآن،
and I still love watching this one.
ولا زلت أحب مشاهدة ذلك.
This was our first six-second, reasonably coherent flight.
كانت تلك الثوان الست الأولى لنا، تحليق متماسك بشكل معقول.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
That was the point where this endeavor went from:
تلك كانت النقطة التي ذهب عندها مسعانا من:
"I'm really not sure this is going to work,"
"أنا لست متأكدا إن كان سيفلح هذا،"
to: "Oh my god, it does work!"
إلى: "يا إلهي، إنه ينجح!"
From there on we then refined it,
عندها شرعنا في تحسين النموذج،
but we carried on falling over a lot.
ولكننا استمرينا في السقوط كثيرا.
Falling over, like I say, is definitely the best way to learn.
السقوط، كما أقول، بشكل مؤكد هو أفضل طريقة للتعلم.
After a while, we starting really refining the layout of all of this.
بعد مرور بعض الوقت،شرعنا في تحسين مخطط الشروع ككل.
And you'll see, that's stability and control --
وسترون، التحكم والثبات --
there's no wires there or anything --
لا توجد هناك أحبال أو أي شيء آخر --
that's a combination of us refining the technology,
الأمر كان مزيجا بيننا لتحسين التقنية،
including with a Tupperware box on the back for the electronics
متضمنا صندوق الأطباق كخلفية للإليكترونيات
and actually learning the balance and control.
وعمليا، تعلم التوازن والتحكم.
I'm now going to save your ears for the next short piece
الآن سوف أحافظ على سلامة آذانكم للمقطع القصير القادم
and talk over it.
وسأغطي عليه بصوتي.
After a while, the jet engine noise is a bit annoying.
بعد برهة، صوت المحرك يصبح مزعجا قليلا.
This is only a few weeks ago.
هذا من عدة أسابيع قليلة.
You can see the stability and control is really quite nice,
يمكنكم أن تروا الثبات والتحكم لطيفان جدا،
and I'd like to think this somewhat validates that starting hypothesis,
وأحب أن أفكر في أن ذلك يثبت صحة فرضية البدء،
that the human mind and body, if properly augmented in that way,
أن العقل والجسد البشري، لو تم تعزيزهما بشكل ملائم،
can achieve some pretty cool stuff.
يمكنهما تحقيق أشياء رائعة.
I mean, like I said:
أعني، كما قلت:
I'm not thinking about where I'm moving my arms at that stage.
عند هذه المرحلة، أنا لا أفكر إلى أين يتحرك ذراعي.
I'm looking at the objective of where I want to get to,
أنا أنظر إلى الهدف الذي أريد أن أذهب إليه،
and a bit like riding a bike,
وتقريبا كما نقود الدراجة الهوائية،
my arms are just doing their thing.
تقومان يدي بالمثل.
It's a very strange experience.
إنها خبرة غريبة جدا.
So where is all this headed?
حسنا، إلى أين يقود كل ذلك؟
I'll talk over this landing --
سأغطي بحديثي على هذه الهبوط --
I think I land in this one.
أعتقد أنني هبطت على هذا.
Well, I don't think anybody's going to go down to Walmart
حسنا، أنا لا أعتقد أن أحدهم سيذهب إلى -ولمارت-
or take the kids to school in any of this stuff for a while,
أو يقل الأولاد إلى المدرسة ياستخدام هذه الإشياء، حاليا،
but the team at Gravity are building some awesome technology
ولكن فريق (الجاذبية) يقومون ببناء أشياء رائعة،
that's going to make this look like child's play.
هذا سيجعل الأمر كلعب الأطفال.
We're working on some things
عاكفون على بعض الأمور
that will seek to bring this unusual experience of flight
والتي تسعى لجلب خبرة تحليق غير مألوفة
to a wider audience, beyond the events and displays we're doing.
لجمهور أكثر اتساعا، وراء المناسبات والعروض التي نقوم بها.
We're even starting to look for pilots two and three,
حتى أننا قمنا بالنظر في النموذج الثاني والثالث،
if there's any volunteers.
لو هناك أي متطوعون.
I've got this vision.
لدي هذه الرؤية.
It sounds audacious, but let's just stick it out there,
يبدو ذلك تهورا، ولكن لنفكر في ذلك،
that one day maybe we can rise up above a beach,
أنه ربما في يوم ما يمكننا أن نحلق فوق شاطيء،
fly up and down the coastline of it, rise up a bit higher,
نذهب إلى الساحل، ونذهب لأعلى قليلا،
with some of the safety kit we're working on to make this achievable.
مع مجموعة من أدوات السلامة، نعمل على نجعل ذلك قابل للتحقيق.
Then over the horizon comes a Hercules with the ramp down.
ثم يأتي شخصا من الأفق منحدرا كهرقل.
As it comes past, you start picking up speed
وأثناء مروره، تبدأ في مجاراة السرعة
and see if we can intercept --
ونري إذا كنا نستطيع التوقف --
from the rear, not the front, that would be a mistake --
من المؤخرة، وليس المقدمة، فذلك سيكون خطأ --
and then try and land in the back.
ونحاول بعدها أن نهبط في الخلف.
And as I say, that's a little way off at the moment.
وكما أقول، هذا بعيد جدا في اللحظة الراهنة.
But this is also, if I take a big step back from this,
ولكن هذا أيضا، لو ابتعدت عن الأمر خطوة كبير إلى الخلف،
this is also a very personal journey for me.
الأمر يعد أيضا رحلة شخصية بالنسبة لي.
Back to that lovely photo,
عودة للصورة الجميلة،
or photo in a picture.
أو الصورة التي باللوحة.
Sadly, my father took his own life when I was 15,
للأسف، قام أبي بالإنتحار وأنا في الخامسة عشر من عمري،
and left an awful lot of unfulfilled ambition.
وترك خلفه كم هائل من الطموح غير المدرك.
He was a wonderful inventor,
كان مخترعا رائعا،
a maverick creator.
وصانع متمرد.
And I'd just like to think, if it was possible,
وأحب أن أفكر، لو كان في الإمكان،
if he was looking down,
لو أنه ينظر لأسفل،
he would be --
قد يكون --
he'd certainly be smiling at some of the things we've done here,
مؤكدا سيكون مبتسما لبعض الأشياء التي حققناها هنا،
I think.
أظن ذلك.
So, it's a tribute to him.
حسنا، فهذا إهداء له.
Thank you very much.
أشكركم شكرا جزيلا
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
(Voice-over) Richard Browning: I'm probably more nervous
(تعليق صوتي) (ريتشارد براونينج): محتمل أنني متوترا أكثر
about doing the demo after this.
للقيام بالتجربة بعد هذا.
I've got a lot of things to get done today.
لدي العديد من الأشياء للقيام بها اليوم.
Worst-case scenario, we don't get a clean start.
الإحتمال الأسوا، أن لا نبدأ بداية ناجحة.
Or we get an unplanned failure while I'm actually flying around.
أو نتعرض لفشل غير مخطط بينما أحلق في المحيط.
This is why we keep it very low,
لهذا نقوم بالتحليق بإرتفاع منخفض،
so the worst is I just look like an idiot and fall on my rear, as I said.
فيكون أسوأ احتمال أن أسقط كالأبلة على ظهري، كما قلت.
So you can all enjoy that if that happens.
فيمكنكم الإستمتاع بالمشهد لو حدث ذلك.
(Music)
(موسيقى)
(Jet engine accelerates)
(محرك الطائرة يتسارع)
(Cheers)
(تحية)